Okay, now we are going to make the jacket
For the jacket, it's almost the same as the baseball uniform
I just made the shoulder a little bit wider
Okay, here we also need to use a fixing pin
And then take the clothes apart a little bit
And then fold it with the fixing pin
It's a good idea to refer to the length and width after it's folded
If you don't think it's appropriate, you can widen it a little bit
This is also, you can add more fixing pins
See if you think it's wide enough when you turn this collar down
Thank you for your support, Zhang Jinbao, thank you
Okay, also fold the collar
Uncovered clothes
Yes, anyway, I want to do it
Well, because I looked at it, I have a lot of illusions
Yes, anyway, I want to do it, because I looked at it, I have a lot of illusions
I think it's a very detailed concept art
They don't wear their jackets well
So I thought about it, then I will also make a jacket that doesn't look good
Okay, then refer to it
In fact, sometimes you will see my operating habits
Sometimes I will be in this
Spinning aimlessly in 3D space
In general, this kind of spinning process is
Ah, will the live broadcast be blocked?
It shouldn't be, I've turned on the white film, it shouldn't be
In the process of my spinning, I'm usually looking for inspiration
Just thinking, oh, what should it look like
Then I decided to make him a collar first
How do we make our collar here?
No, no, it shouldn't be
Make a collar, start from this point
Turn down, you see
Are we opening the collar now?
After opening it, go back to the back
Let's take a look at this curve
Oh, thank you, thank you
Thank you, thank you for this little friend
Thank you for the little friend whose name can't be read
Thank you for the fan sign you voted for
Um, it starts from this point in the back
Down
When we turn this collar over
You see if his curve is going down from this point
So when we are drawing the 2D version
It also goes down from this point, understand?
And then the length is the same as the length we just selected
Okay, after drawing this version, control D
Create a symmetrical version
Then in the process of sewing, press the shift key
You can sew a whole section and multiple sections
Okay, after sewing, arrange this version on the side
And then when you arrange it on the side, what about it?
It may, um, that is to say
It may affect the position of our previously added fixing needles
So let's freeze the big body first
Let the collar automatically sew it up
Then simulate
Okay, I don't know if you found it just now
I didn't sew it in the back
Because we are now in a collar
Are relatively open
Then add this line to the back of the collar
What we just created is
When we were creating here in the back
I drew this line with my own hands
Then sometimes we will say
When we are folding the collar
You will find that no matter how you fold this collar, you can't turn it over, right?
You will definitely encounter this situation many times
You just think that my inner line
The inner line used to fold
No matter how you draw it, it doesn't work
It just goes back
Why?
It's actually because of the shape of your collar.
Sometimes your collar has a pointy corner there
Then you use the inner line to draw it and then fold it down
This pointy corner is still there
It can't be folded very well
You use the folding tool
Sometimes it will go back
At this time, I will remind you in the group
Then we first put this line in the back
First put this line
This pink line is deleted
Then we use the folding tool to fold the collar
Take a look at it
How does it turn in the form of natural
After turning it over, this piece is what we just automatically turned over
Is this piece missing a triangular structure, right?
That is to say, if we want this collar to turn over naturally
Let's put it together
Yes, just like what was said in the bulletin
We disassemble to solve the problem
First, let the panel be loosened
It's folded
Then we fill in the missing part
So if you find that the collar
No matter how you fold this collar
If it doesn't turn right
Then we might as well delete the pink line in the back
Then fold it first
Then fill in the missing part
For example, I found that it lacks a triangle here
Then we just keep expanding this point out
Let it fill this panel out
OK
Then sew the two sides together
Now I can do it very naturally
Let it be loose
This collar is also turned over
There will be no stretching or something that looks weird
This is what I give you about the collar
This is some tips I give you about the collar
You know
So everyone is usually doing shirts
Or do this kind of coat jacket
In the process
If you think this collar is always
If you can't turn it over
Then you can cancel the pink line first
Then take a look
Is it the panel itself?
There is no way to fold it right
OK
After that, I was thinking
Oh, what does this coat look like?
Then I thought about it
Then let's put the panel and the zipper part on first
Then make the middle part of it a cologne layer
OK
I said this structure is like this
Here
This part of the structure
This one is the zipper
This is the panel
Then this is the coat
So we are going to draw two inner lines
A inner line is used to sew this panel
This zipper
Of course, I drew the arrow upside down
I hope you can understand
OK
Draw the inner line
After that
Let's draw another zipper next to it
OK
Then about its width
We just
Just fill it up
Then put the collar here
Then close all the
We each have our own way
To make a circle
We dig in
Here let's just place it on the center
Yes
We only have these two pieces, so we don't need to make the cologne layer for these two pieces.
After that, it's also here, let's cut it and sew it.
Then we copy and paste the cologne layer, and then use the line sewing tool to sew it.
For this type of sewing line, we need to choose TURN, because they are stacked together, and they are sewed on the same side, so we need to change the type of sewing line to TURN.
Otherwise, it may not be stable.
After that, I think about it, oh, the cologne layer should be...
The reference I saw, the cologne layer should be narrower, so I changed the cologne layer to be narrower.
Then, in order to easily distinguish these pieces, so I gave them the same fabric, but with a different color.
Then there is a loop, and then because of this piece, they are...
It's just that in order to easily distinguish the right and the wrong, so I chose to display it on one side.
So in the process of everyone's usual operation,
Hey, how come I didn't react when I added the thickness?
It's because you're looking at a single-sided display.
You can't display the thickness.
Do you understand?
So at this time, you can switch to display thickness by pressing Alt 1.
Then in the cologne layer, here I use the cologne layer method, because I want to quickly make a zipper part.
So I used the cologne layer, and then cut it off with the inner line.
Of course, before you cut it off, remember to cancel the link first.
Or if you don't cancel the link, it will also be removed by itself.
It doesn't matter.
And then I'm using the cologne layer method here because I want to steal it.
When you use the cologne layer tool, there will naturally be a line between the board and the board.
There is a circle of lines.
After that, even if we cut this board in the middle,
The original circle of lines,
That is, it still has the position of the cologne line.
In this way, we don't need to manually sew the zipper again.
Do you understand?
Okay, so I'm done with the zipper part of this board.
I'm going to start making the cologne layer.
Okay, change the fabric for him.
Let's change the color for him.
Let's make a distinction again.
These few boards.
First of all, let's make a layer of cologne for him.
Make a layer of cologne.
Before we make the cologne layer here, we can give it to him first.
Because our previous conflict thickness is 2.5.
Now I'm going to make a layer of cologne for him inside.
Note that I chose the inside of the cologne layer here.
Because if we sew the pocket outside now,
Then if you use the outside of the cologne layer,
Then the pocket will add a layer between the cologne and the clothes itself.
It will cause instability.
So if your clothes...
And we will make the pocket before we fold it or fold it.
Put the pocket on first.
Otherwise, you can't put the pocket in at the end.
Because the pocket is relatively small.
And it is relatively flat.
It is not easy to be unstable.
If it is a large structure,
For example, if you make a cologne layer,
Then you fold it and then do it.
Of course, this is a little different from the knot.
Just to say.
Then after we make the cologne layer,
You have to remember to reduce our conflict thickness.
Then simulate it again.
In the simulation process,
Why did I make a layer of cologne here?
It's because of our...
My last file.
Let me show you a project file.
Wait a minute.
The last project file.
Its jacket here.
Especially here.
We can't see the seam.
It's the seam inside this layer.
So we actually have three layers in total.
The first layer is the outer layer.
It looks like a thick jacket.
Then this layer.
There are two layers here.
Linear panels.
So we need to cologne a layer first.
Go inside and do this.
The basic layer of the linear panel.
Remember to cancel the link after cologne.
Because if they have a link relationship,
You delete these lines in the pocket.
When replaced with a linear pattern.
It will.
Delete with the body.
So here we cancel the link.
Then set them themselves as symmetrical panels.
It doesn't matter.
We still have to.
Think about it for a while.
So it doesn't matter if you're late.
Now if you delete the panels.
It won't affect the outer layer.
But when you delete.
This is not deleting panels.
Delete the inner line.
Then the grid will be re-placed.
When your grid is re-placed.
After that.
Then it may have.
There is a connection problem at the top of the grid.
So remember to open the simulation.
Understand?
So don't think.
Why just delete one inner line.
It's unstable.
It's because when you delete the inner line.
Sometimes it will affect the position of the grid.
It's just a little bit of a change.
But if you put it together.
When it's on a lot of messy panels.
It may be unstable.
So delete the inner line.
You have to simulate it habitually.
OK.
Here we see when it's unstable.
Remember to intervene.
Let it stop interfering with each other.
It's unstable.
And you should find.
I didn't use it here.
I didn't use the layer to deal with it.
It's because of this kind of panel.
It's very close to the panel.
And they're still together.
It's not an independent structure.
If you use the layer.
Although it can be stable.
But once they cross each other.
It's very unstable.
Because when they cross each other.
The back and front of the panel.
Sometimes.
Especially like this kind of clothes.
It's turned over.
Its back is outwards.
First of all.
When you're setting the layer.
There may be some doubts.
I don't know if it's set as a positive number or a negative number.
The second is that it's in an unstable position.
It's easy to cross itself.
You use the layer.
It will be more unstable.
So if it's just a little bit of instability at the beginning.
Then we use our hands.
Just drag it by hand.
Just fix it.
So when you're doing it.
You need to focus a little bit.
See where it's unstable.
Try to intervene.
And then here.
Because we wait.
If you directly cross the layer.
The middle part of it.
It will automatically form a seam line.
Yes.
After merging.
The seam line on the strap will also disappear.
So you.
These are all to pay attention to.
Okay.
After merging.
You're on the dragon floor.
The line in the middle of it.
It's not going to be there.
Then my.
It's here in the back.
Here in the back.
If you want it to be a complete version.
I'm going to merge at this point.
Remember.
Then I think.
He keeps this line.
I think I'm more inclined.
I like this structure better.
So I didn't merge it.
Then the surface of the virtual model.
Reduce a little.
Reduce to zero.
This is because I'm now.
Another one.
I'm doing a project file.
You can see me for.
Because of the previous version.
Although the number of versions.
I'm frozen.
But because the number of versions is still there.
Plus.
We reduced the particle diameter before.
If you go directly to the structure of the file just now.
If you do it.
It's a waste of time.
So when I'm doing it here.
I'm looking at another file.
Then you have to remember.
Let the virtual model.
This surface.
The surface diameter.
Fits the surface diameter of your other file.
Otherwise.
When you put it outside.
He needs to calculate again.
The surface diameter.
It will also affect your.
This is the resolution effect.
It may be a little unstable.
Then.
A layer in the column.
The inner layer of the column.
That's it.
Okay.
Here.
It's also.
Remind you again.
If you want to do it later.
The result of the merger.
Remember to merge here.
Okay.
After that.
We are in the inner layer of the column.
Let's see.
The inner layer of the column.
Like before.
We do.
The sleeve of the previous version.
It's the same.
But at this time.
If you are in the process of simulation.
You are in the inner layer of the column.
After that.
I found it unstable.
Because I frozen the external version.
To do it faster.
To calculate.
And then.
If you find it unstable.
Then.
You can simulate it all.
If you have any questions.
You can ask.
All of them.
The overall version.
All.
Activated simulation.
Then the particle diameter is reduced a little bit.
Continue to simulate.
It's usually.
Our software is called Mammoth Designer.
And then its abbreviation is.
MDRE.
How to get the grid out.
You can wait for the subsequent.
This playback.
Take a look.
I'm using the inner line.
Draw.
Draw a row.
Then.
Ctrl C.
Ctrl V.
Right click.
You can enter the number.
Then enter the number.
Here.
It is suitable for sewing sleeves.
Almost.
Here.
You see.
I use the internal line first.
Then.
Ctrl C.
Ctrl V.
Right click.
To enter the number.
Then.
Enter the number.
After that.
Here.
You see.
Ourھ can enter the number.
Then.
Check.
Right click.
Lining to the outside.
Then.
Double machine internal line.
And then.
Then.
Double-click on the inner line, then double-click again to select all the inner lines on the panel, then ctrl-c, ctrl-r, ctrl-r, ctrl-r, ctrl-r, ctrl-r, and then put it on, put it on, and then it will have a zero star grid, and then you are in the column layer, because the inner line, when you use the column layer, the inner line on the panel will also be cloned out at the same time, and the inner line will also form a powder line between the inner line and the inner line, so that it will form a natural zero-shaped combination position.
Okay, after we have cloned it, if you need to make it shrink a little, along the powder line, there are some wrinkles, then you can select all the inner lines, and then the inner lines with zero-shaped grid lines, and then apply the elasticity to them.
Click on the elasticity, and then set the value to 98 or 95, give it a little bit,
and then the value is set to 98 or 95, give it a little bit,
Next, you can also increase the shrink rate of the gold-plated sand on this side of the board so that it can also form some folds due to the difference in the size of the board.
Then, in order to make the effect of inflating, we used negative pressure on the inside of the board, and positive pressure on the outside of the board to form an inflating effect.
For those of you who don't know how to use pressure, you can take a look at the explanation of pressure in our skill sharing section.
It's more clear and clear.
Next, let's take a look at the shrink rate.
I just mentioned that we can use the shrink rate to make the fold become richer.
Now, let's take a look at how the shrink rate affects.
First of all, this board is now at a shrink rate of 100.
The overall size is about the same as the inner board.
So its fold is relatively flat.
There is a certain fold, but there is a fold, but not much.
Not every fold is the same.
If you watch our live broadcast every Friday, there is not so much content.
You can follow our account.
Some videos are posted on the Bilibili account.
Then, let's take a look at the shrink rate.
Because when you increase the shrink rate, the board is in this direction.
It has two directions, level and value.
Usually, in Marvelous Designer,
the direction of the value of the created board is the golden direction,
and the direction of the level is the end direction.
Then, you can increase the shrink rate like this
to make the board temporarily larger than the inner board.
Then, after increasing its shrink rate,
it will become wider because the board is getting bigger.
It is integrated with the board inside.
Hmm?
I don't know what you guys are talking about.
No, no.
It is because I am doing these live broadcasts and videos alone in China.
And there is the technical support of the group.
So, in addition to that,
sometimes I may be a little busy,
testing and so on.
So, doing live broadcasts every week is obviously...
Right?
Okay.
Hmm.
Can we not adjust the length and width of the board
after only changing the shrink rate?
Yes.
Because our overall size is OK now.
We just let the board have a certain wrinkle.
And our board is a multi-layer structure,
so you can increase the shrink rate of the inner layer you can see.
For example, the inner board is a small one,
and the outer board is a large one.
So, you can make it a small one.
The shrink rate is not for the time being.
What I am talking about is that you can temporarily increase the shrink rate.
You can use this effect to determine how much you want to give the shrink rate.
You can give 105,
you can give 101,
you can give 102.
It all depends on the effect you want at the end.
The shrink rate can of course be put there all the time.
But,
for example,
if you give the board a shrink rate of 200,
it looks like a normal size,
and there is only one layer of clothing between you,
then it means that your board is originally small.
Then you need to manually increase the size of the board.
You can't say that this board,
I have a shrink rate of 200 there,
and a shrink rate of 300 there,
it is a fit for the human body curve.
I have to keep this.
Because when you give a shrink rate,
your grid will stretch,
and your UV picture may not match.
Do you understand?
Let's take a look at it.
No,
the clothes are black.
Wait a minute.
I'll show you like this,
and you'll understand.
For example,
this is a board,
right?
There is a playback today.
For example,
there is a board now,
and then,
this is the surface of its frame.
If you give a shrink rate,
for example,
you gave a measure,
oh,
let's give a little more,
for example,
150,
the final shrink rate,
you can see that this board,
its grid will be stretched.
For example,
your final shrink rate and the final shrink rate are all provided to 150.
This grid is actually equal to the width and width of the variable.
But in the 2D window,
its UV is still like this.
So it will affect your calculation effect.
But if this value,
you are adjusting a very large value,
then sometimes you need to consider
whether your version is really too small.
Why did it suddenly turn over?
What are you doing?
All right,
let's not look at this first.
It just stuck in that position.
Yes,
that's right.
So you need to know,
if you have this board,
the shrink rate you use must be,
that is,
your shrink rate must be given to 200.
And it's only one layer.
If it's wearing normal,
then the way to use the shrink rate,
your way of using it is wrong.
The way I use the shrink rate is that I have two layers of board,
and then I put the outer layer,
make the outer layer a little bigger,
it will have some rich wrinkles.
Then the wrinkles will be generated.
Okay,
then we'll just manually drag it around.
Is the inner line of the grid drawn one by one?
No,
you didn't,
did you just go to the bathroom and didn't see it?
I've demonstrated it twice.
After you draw a line,
ctrl c, ctrl v,
ctrl v,
then right click,
I can't show you,
ctrl v,
then right click,
you can enter a specific number,
you can set the root number of this column.
Do you understand?
Who doesn't believe it?
Look back,
look back.
Yes,
and now our jacket,
if you take off a small basket,
use a fabric for it.
Here we use
polyester taffeta,
that is,
this fabric,
you can take a look at our Chinese,
Chinese,
we also use polyester tape.
That's x Liverpool,
yes,
I don't want to call you the third time,
let's go see the elbow response board,
ah,
this physical properties ah,
polyester
taffeta
ah,
this physical properties,
it's a physical properties of our common inflat Te
Let's take a closer look and talk about this, it's not easy to stretch, sometimes people think that the fabric that is not easy to stretch is that its folds are relatively rough or are relatively thin.
In fact, it is not like that, the same fabric that is not easy to stretch, you can imagine, for example,
the fold is not easy to stretch, it is very hard, its folds are rough, but the windbreaker, its jacket is also not easy to stretch,
but its folds are much thinner than the fold, this is the difference in the strength of the fold.
So when you are adjusting the fabric, you must pay attention to its texture and the texture of the fold.
Yes, you may need to adjust by bending strength and mastering the stretch power.
Our lessons have already started, and then they are all uploaded into the video mode for the first day.
If you are interested in understanding how it works, you can see the tutorial video.
But I recommend you for the first 2 days because the third day is very attractive.
As you see?
After the 미 bumpedo you take a look and decide if you need to increase your this condition.
a more detailed course
to think about whether or not to buy it.
Everyone should buy it in a rational way.
Got it?
Okay.
And then the sleeves, also give it a Cologne layer.
After that, we will turn this jacket back on.
Oh, it's not a jacket, the clothes inside are all back on.
We're going to add the jacket in.
This is to choose to add clothing.
The virtual model doesn't need to be added, because it already has it.
Because the top of the clothes inside is relatively close-fitting,
so we don't need to make too many adjustments to the top.
You just activate the top,
and then give the top a negative layer,
so that it doesn't wear out.
Okay, let's simulate this.
The top part is tight, so the problem is not big.
Okay, after the simulation,
remember to return the layer to zero.
Okay.
Then we add a fixing needle on both sides.
First, let the clothes and this one,
we don't want to have a gap between the pieces of the knot.
The back-activated pieces,
it doesn't have a gap effect,
and it won't be affected by the shape.
So now we have the lower half of the clothes back-activated.
You can see that they are all dark blue.
Let's manually put this jacket,
and adjust its position.
Okay.
After we don't want it to have a gap between the pieces of the knot,
let's untie the other pieces.
Okay.
Not untie,
but activate it.
Because it was back-activated just now.
Activate it.
After activating it,
let's delete the fixing needle,
and simulate it again.
Okay, when we simulate it,
here we find another problem.
Then I will,
this is what I mentioned to you before.
If you make a multi-layer structure,
especially when the tightening is more powerful,
it will be easy to be unstable.
Because Hana's hair,
the double tail is also relatively sharp,
it will always be a little tight.
So we are lucky to
first anti-activate the inner layer of this square plate.
After they are all stabilized,
we will activate the inner layer part,
and then add it to the inside,
and let it stick to the inside.
Yes, I am using anti-activation here.
First, the inner layer of this layer is anti-activated,
so that it does not participate in the simulation.
Then we will reserve the conflict thickness.
In fact, it is the same as the sleeve,
which is the same as the waist plate.
Okay,
let's remove the hardening
that was used to make the pocket fit better.
Okay.
Then freeze the inner layer of the plate,
because they have always been relatively stable.
Okay.
Then we do the fold effect.
Finally, we put the inner layer of this layer
with this,
with the arrangement of
the added function,
the plate is added to the inside.
Okay.
In the simulation process,
we can drag it a little bit.
We can drag the fixing needle.
Okay.
After adding the fixing needle,
we use the sewing needle to fix the position of this plate a little bit.
Okay.
Why do we need to use the sewing needle to fix it here?
Because we are going to switch the action now.
Because if you put the inner layer of the plate
on the inside of the fur coat before switching the action,
not the fur coat,
but the fur coat inside the fur coat,
if you put the fur coat on the inside of the fur coat,
then you have to change the action later.
Because sometimes the action is relatively large,
it may have some wear and tear problems.
In order to prevent these wear and tear problems,
we can change the action first.
After the action is fixed and stable,
then add the inner layer of the fur coat.
Okay.
Now we activate all the plates.
Then change the position.
Here we choose to only change the position.
This position,
I can manually change it by pressing Shift X in Marvelous Designer.
Then wait for it to simulate a little bit.
Because after you change the position,
the clothing plate will follow your position change,
and it will have some simulation and calculation.
After it is stable,
freeze all the unrelated plates,
and activate the outer layer of the fur coat.
Because,
let me mention again,
the difference between freeze and anti-aggression,
the freeze plate will have some conflict.
The anti-aggression plate will not.
That is,
the plate will pass directly from the anti-aggression plate,
or pass through.
But if the plate is freeze,
although the shape will not change,
but it will still have the effect of wearing and tearing.
Not wearing and tearing,
but the effect of conflict.
It can prevent the plate from passing through.
Okay.
After we have changed our movement,
we choose the inner layer of the plate,
and add it to the side.
But note that,
because we have reserved the conflict thickness before,
the conflict thickness of 2.5.
Now we have changed the conflict thickness to 1,
and then add it to the side.
The principle is the same as when we did the waist knot before.
If you don't know,
the waist knot,
if you don't know how to operate it,
you can go back and look at the replay.
Okay.
Add it to the inside.
Because we have reserved the conflict thickness,
now after we cut the conflict thickness,
you can simulate it.
It is a more stable form.
Then we have to pay attention to see
if it has any other unstable places.
If not,
we can pause the simulation.
Okay.
Then reduce the particle diameter again.
The smaller the particle diameter,
the more it can avoid some small unstable places.
Because sometimes there are some small places,
it is because,
for example,
the inner line is very small,
and then you sew the inner line together,
and then its network gap is not enough,
so it is easy to be unstable.
Then you imagine,
when you reduce the particle diameter,
will its network gap increase?
Then it is not easy to be unstable.
Because the network gap is large.
Can you understand?
So in a more stable situation,
reduce its particle diameter first,
so that we can effectively prevent it from being unstable.
Then why don't I do this set of operations
before I change the action?
It's because if we put this kind of multi-layered clothing,
after its overall particle diameter is reduced,
then if we change its action,
will it be the same as before?
Yes, it will be the same as before.
It will be the same as before.
Okay.
Then,
when we change the action,
will the speed of its simulation slow down?
And we have to adjust some of its physical shapes,
these will all be affected.
So we will do these adjustments
when the particle diameter is relatively large.
Finally,
we will do its stability well.
So you don't have to worry.
If you are doing animation,
then you just need to know that
when you are doing it,
you can reduce the particle diameter first.
Then when you are making sleeves here,
you can adjust the speed of the movement.
Because I think its shape now is...
I have adjusted its strength of the gold-plated gauze
relatively high,
and then it also has a low bending strength.
So it looks a little bit hard overall.
I hope its sleeves look softer.
So I have reduced its gold-plated gauze rate a little bit.
Oh, the strength of the gold-plated gauze is not the rate,
but the strength of the gold-plated gauze is reduced a little bit.
It looks softer and smoother.
But I still want to keep its thick texture.
But if you want its texture to look not so thick,
but thinner,
then you can reduce the bending strength.
Because I didn't choose to reduce the bending strength here.
Okay,
then it's the part of its pants.
As for the part of the pants,
it's also because of my personal preference.
I adjusted its position a little bit.
You can see that its chest area is still relatively large.
I adjusted its chest area manually here.
I will send a reminder first when I stream.
I will post it on Bilibili.
There is a preview,
and then there is a WeChat public number,
and then there is a QQ.
So if you don't know,
then there is a possibility that
you don't follow our Bilibili,
and then there is a WeChat account.
The pants here are the same.
Because I think it's a little too dark.
I want a softer effect,
so I will reduce its bending strength to 2000.
Then manually adjust its position.
Great, Zhang Jinbao.
Thank you for being with me today.
I will remember your account.